

**Burak Kanmaz** 

Technology Consultant



+90 (538) 778 90 86



burak@kanmaz.net



12 Apr, 1987

Burak, who is married and has a child, has worked professionally on Microsoft technologies for over 13 years. At the same time, he works by following trend technologies regularly and being open to innovations. With his innovative personality, he attaches great importance to quality, performance, and efficiency in all his work. He also applies this working principle in team and project management.

## **Work Experiences**

# **Technology Consultant**

Freelance January, 2023 - ....

He provides software consultancy and Jira consultancy to domestic and foreign companies.

In this context, Jira Plugin, Teams App, and Slack App products were developed. At the same time, he continues to provide consultancy services by continuing his certification studies on Jira and Azure.



#### **Head of Technology**

Inooster April, 2022 - January, 2023

He worked as the Head of Technology at Turkey's largest company in gamification solutions. After starting the business, he helped the company take its gamification experience to different platforms by developing products in Jira.

He followed and managed the company's 5 products and more than 20 customer portfolios, products, and technical processes of customers. He worked with 2 software teams affiliated with him.



## Team Lead

Antasya May, 2021 - April, 2022

As the Team Lead of the 7-person software team that develops tailor-made software for corporate companies, he managed the works and customers. He provided the follow-up, management, and customer communication of 15 projects of 5 corporate companies, including 3 holdings, 1 bank, and 1 production facility.

In addition to team management, he also undertook the responsibility of all technical work within the company. Accordingly, he took an active role in the recovery and management of all physical and digital technical assets of the company, the technical coordination of other teams, and the determination of the company's future plans.

In addition to these, he took part in all technical communication and management processes with customers during his duty. Helped grow internal teams by interviewing more than 75 jobs. With his experience on the Jira side, he enabled the company to provide Jira Consulting to its clients.



# **Solutions Architect**

Ericsson May, 2017 - Apr, 2021

He started to work as a Senior Software Developer within a team of 20 people in the call center flow management

#### Areas of Interest and Expertise

### **Backend Technologies**

.NET Framework, .NET Core, Node JS, ASP.NET MVC, C#, Java

#### **Frontend Technologies**

React JS, Angular, Bootstrap, Typescript

#### **Mobile Technologies**

Flutter, React Native

#### **Data Store/Process Technologies**

EF, MSSQL, PL/SQL, PostreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Solr, Elastic Search (ELK)

### **DevOps Technologies**

Windows Server, IIS, Linux, Docker, Azure, AWS, Cloudflare, Firewall

#### **Project Management Technologies**

Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps, Git, TFS, Bitbucket

#### **Administrative Technologies**

Microsoft 365, Exchange, Teams, Azure, MPN, Cloudflare

## **Other**

Information Security and Pentest, CFP (Cosmic Function Point), Python

## **Technologies He Tries To Lead**

Artificial Intelligence, GPT-4, IoT, Raspberry Pi

## Information Security

He has been working in the field of information security since 2012 for hobby purposes. During these studies, he provided security consultancy and pentest services to many companies. In addition to information security; He also consulted on social engineering, penetration testing, network security, and application security. Some of the companies he serves;















project of Turkcell, Turkey's largest GSM operator.

In October 2017, he became the person responsible for one of the critical modules within the project. During the year he worked in this position, he took the responsibility of the business as a contact person with the customer and served as a Lead Developer.

In October 2018, a team was formed to maintain and develop Turkcell Global Bilgi's corporate applications. He served as Solutions Architect at the head of this team, which varied between 10-15 people depending on the project and needs. In this process, he undertook all the processes from the establishment of the team to the management of the relations with the customer. He provided development support and technical support services with his team on 20+ projects for the customer.



### **IT Manager**

#### Istanbul Commodity Exchange 2015 - 2017

He was assigned to manage the information technology team of 5 people and to meet all the software and hardware needs of the company's 120 personnel in 5 different locations.

Reorganized the network infrastructure where security and authorization were not enough. Adjusted user authorizations, maximizing security and authorization by adjusting internet access rules, file shares, and a firewall. In addition, he made it all user actions within the network can be monitored, automatically alerted, and controlled.



## **IT Manager Assistant**

Ankara Sigorta 2014 - 2015

He realized that all source codes and databases could be accessed thanks to a security vulnerability he found on the Ankara Insurance website. Following the notification of this vulnerability, he was assigned to the company's 12-person information technology team as Assistant Manager responsible for the software.

He focused on performance issues in the recently written infrastructure with .NET Framework.



# Senior Software Developer

Doğan Gazetecilik 2012 - 2014

He worked actively during the development of the Live Score project, which was developed on the broadcasting of the live results of sports games, especially football. The project was implemented on MSSQL using ASP.NET MVC. He used Angular JS and Knockout JS so that the scores could be given to the visitors as quickly as possible. Together with NetScaler, he has prepared a system that can serve 65,000 instantaneous visitors without any performance loss.



## Software Developer

Kariyer.net 2012 - 2012



## **Software Developer**

IRM Ajans 2009 - 2012

### **Awards and Achievements**

Ö	Ericsson was awarded a special thank-you for working remotely during the pandemic period.	2020
Ö	Awarded Ericsson's "MMEA's 2019 Champions Award Winner"	2019
<b>T</b>	Won 1st place in Turkey in Microsoft's international Imagine Cup software competition	2010
*	Selected as Microsoft Student Partner 2 times 2008	, 2009
i	Wrote a book on Windows 7	2008

#### **Educational Background**



Postgraduate Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2022 - ....

He has completed the course phase and is writing a thesis on the subject of "Security Analysis of Blockchain-based Applications".



**Undergraduate** Sociology

Istanbul University 2020 - ....

Due to his interest in sociology and psychology, he studies sociology with remote education.



## Undergraduate

Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2005 - 2010

During his undergraduate life, he served as the computer club president, department student representative and department laboratory assistant.